Manasbir Bagri

+1 (236) 971-0294 | bagrimanasbir@gmail.com | manasbir.github.io | in/manasbir

Summary

Incoming University of Waterloo Mathematics student with 5 years of experience in programming and 3 years specialized in blockchain development. Interested in optimization problems, financial strategies, and public markets. Currently working in MEV and exploring Calculus.

Technical Skills

- Programming Rust, TypeScript (TS), JavaScript (JS), Python, Solidity, Huff, C++, React.js
- Design Figma, Photoshop, Inkscape

Experience

Software Engineer/MEV, Protecc Labs | Full-time/Part-time, June 2023 - Present

- Earned \$100,000+ by implementing and optimizing MEV strategies in Rust.
- Managed \$500,000+ by creating market maker functionality in Rust and TypeScript.
- Saved 300% computation time in MEV strategies by optimizing the multi-threaded implementations in Rust.

Contract Development, Self-employed | Part-time May 2022 - Present

- Created a protocol with \$1.2+ million TVL using Solidity and Javascript.
- Helped rescue funds by developing programs using Rust.
- Secured 50+ first bids on NFTs by creating and optimizing strategies in TypeScript.

Software Engineering Internship, mtx.gg | Full-time, April 2022 - July 2022

- Created turn-based blockchain games using Solidity.
- Optimized Solidity code by minimizing storage and memory reads and writes.

Projects

Offline-Wallet (github.com/cesarhuret/offline-wallet) | ETHWaterloo 2023

• Facilitated offline cross-chain Ethereum payments using QR codes with an app built in React Native and account abstraction infrastructure built in Solidity.

UNAI, AI calendar/planner (github.com/manasbir/unai) | 2023-2024

• Calendar that would adapt and learn to your specific needs, built with TypeScript, Next.js, Tailwind, and GPT 3.5 to chat and add events to the calendar.

Watccha, Ethereum Wallet Tracker (github.com/manasbir/watccha) | 2023

 Modular Ethereum wallet monitoring tool with generalized calldata decoding and email notifications with the ability to react on-chain, built with Rust and GPT 3.5 for decoding into natural language.

Education

Mathematics (Honours) Co-op, University of Waterloo | Sept 2024 - Present

• Incoming

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme (IB DP), Johnston Heights | Sept 2022 - May 2024

• Courses: Mathematics AA HL, Chemistry HL, Physics HL

- President of Clubs: Touching Grass Club, Model UN, Robotics Club, and Business Club
- Final Grade: TBD/45

Interests

- **Optimization**: Code, Open-source contributions, Square Root Algorithms (Hobby and Math Project), PvP Tetris (Top 1% APP), Speedcubing (PB: sub-15s), Jungling in League of Legends
- Philosophy and Enlightenment: Touching Grass, Looking at the Sky, Meditation, and Reading
- **Prev. Competitions** (Won prizes at all): ETHDenver 2022 & 2023, NwHacks HackCamp 2023, ETHSanFrancisco 2023, ETHNewYork 2023, ETHWaterloo 2023, and Paradigm CTF 2022